Guide to the Mount Vernon Seminary and College Student Government Association records, 1982-1997 MVC0038.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mount Vernon Seminary and College Student Government Association records
1982-1997
1992-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MVC0038.RG
2.25 Linear Feet 4 document boxes and 1 slim document box
This collection contains records of the Student Government Association at Mount Vernon Seminary and College. The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999. The materials date from 1982-1997, with the bulk of the collection ranging from 1992-1996. This collection is from Mount Vernon College, which George Washington University acquired in 1999.
Historical note
The Student Government Association of Mount Vernon College was the governing council of the student body and a forum for the expression of student opinion, projects, events, and concerns to the college administration and faculty. It was also responsible for introducing appropriate policies in the interest of students.
The Mount Vernon Seminary began in 1875 as a private high school and junior college for women, founded by Elizabeth J. Somers. The George Washington University initially affiliated with Mount Vernon College, and ultimately acquired the college's property and legacy in 1999.
The first school of higher education available to women in Washington, D.C., Mount Vernon Seminary and College had five different locations throughout its history:
1875-1880: Elizabeth Somers began tutoring the young daughters of prominent Washington men in her home at 204 F Street, NW in Washington, DC.
1880-1917: The school moved to 1100 M Street, NW where it expanded rapidly to include three additional houses, a courtyard, tennis court, and basketball court.
1917-1942: Having outgrown its M Street location, the school moved to a 15-acre campus on Nebraska Avenue, NW. In 1942, the United States Navy took over the Nebraska Avenue campus to use its facilities for the war effort.
1943-1946: The school resumed courses in February 1943 at the top floor of a Garfinckel's department store building in the Spring Valley neighborhood of Washington, D.C.
1946-1999: Between 1944 and 1946, the school built a new 21-acre campus located on Foxhall Road in Washington, D.C. using money granted to the college by the United States Navy in compensation for the military takeover of its property.
The last Seminary class graduated in 1969, and the school was then officially renamed to Mount Vernon Junior College. In 1976, Mount Vernon College became an accredited four year college. In 1997, the Board of Trustees decided that the College would close as an independent institution. As of June 30, 1999, Mount Vernon became affiliated with The George Washington University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection is from Mount Vernon College, which The George Washington University acquired in 1999.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, calendars, receipts, documents on events and programs, correspondence, flyers, and programs. The materials date from 1982-1997, with the bulk of the collection ranging from 1992-1996. The records are related to the Student Government Association and its role encouraging student participation at Mount Vernon College.
Arrangement
This collection is organized chronologically.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Student government; Mount Vernon College
- Senior class silent auction, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Senior class silent auction, 1983 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Senior class silent auction, 1984 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Senior class silent auction, 1985 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Senior class silent auction, 1986 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Senior class silent auction, 1987 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Senior class silent auction, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Senior class silent auction, 1993 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Senior class silent auction catalogue, 1995 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Constitution of the Student Government Association, 1981-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Student Government Association activities reports, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Student Government Association meeting minutes, 1991 September - November (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Constitution of the Student Government Association, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Student Government Association notes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Student Government Association proposals, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Student Government Association information, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Student Government Association agenda and minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Student Government Association events, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Student directory, 1992 Fall (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Black Student Alliance information, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jewel Goodman - President, Junior class, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Clubs and organizations, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Student Government Association - other business, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Student Government Association - beautification and recognition, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Student Government Association minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Student Government Association student leaders, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Student Government Association minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Student Government Association meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Student Government Association executive board, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Mount Vernon College Big/Little Sister program, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Calendar of Tammalyn Thomas, Student Government Association Vice President, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Student Government Association student leaders, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Student Government Association events, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Student Government Association Constitution, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Calendar of Suzanne Brown, Student Government Association President, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Mount Vernon College General Ledger Summary Trial Balance, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mount Vernon College General Ledger Detail Trial Balance, 1992 July 01 - 1993 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Student Government Association agendas and minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Memorandum of Inauguration Committee, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mount Vernon College Inauguration, 1992 September 18 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Student Government Association letters sent, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Student Government Association executive board, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Student Government Association minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Student Government Association receipts, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Student Government Association receipts, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Student Government Association agenda, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Enrollment reports, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Student Government Association agenda, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Calendar, 1995 September - 1996 May (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Student Government Association mail, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Student Government Association minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Student Government Association Transition Ceremony, 1996 April 10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Mount Vernon College Commencement, 1995 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous notes by Jennifer A. Sramowicz, Senior Class President, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Fundraisers, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Mount Vernon College facility set-up forms, 1995 August 22 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Senior class of 1996, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Activities, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Mount Vernon College's Student Government Association Constitution, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Student Government Association directory, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Year end reports, 1996 March - May (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Student Government Association agenda, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Student Government Association phone tree and Board of Trustees, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Student Government Association agendas, 1996 September - December (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Student Government Association notes by Heather Ellsworth, Student Representative to the Board, 1996 Fall (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous notes by Heather Ellsworth, Student Representative to the Board, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)